Tracy Sarah Afram-Owusu

Front-End Developer

Github | aframowusutracysarah@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | +233241595499

Professional summary

A Front-End Developer with three years of experience in web application and software development. My proficiency lies in the ability to analyze customer requirements to design and develop effective, high-end, and user-friendly web solutions. My aptitude for learning is remarkable, enabling me to adapt to constantly changing requirements and environments swiftly. Additionally, I am skilled in working both independently and collaboratively as a team member.

Proj	ect	Ach	iev	em	ent
------	-----	-----	-----	----	-----

- Developed a website for the Cocoa Research Institute of Ghana with a team -CRIG
- Developed a freelance platform with a team to connect African Talents with international clients <u>TheFairWork</u>
- Developed a blog for TheFairWork platform with a team <u>TheFairWork blog</u>
- Developed an online learning platform for students <u>DevTray</u>

Experience

AmaliTech Services, Ghana - Associate Developer

JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

DUTIES

- Development of new applications and services in an agile, collaborative environment
- Work on innovative solutions in software testing, software development, operations, and maintenance.
- Participate in developing or maintaining existing services, systems, databases, and Applications
- Development of software system testing and validation procedures.
- Assist with the analysis, design, and further development of the software architecture, plus the application of design patterns.
- Code and test major features, as well as work jointly with other team members to deliver complex change under tight deadlines.
- Actively participate in the design and further development of the IT landscape in the areas of software development and software testing.
- Code cleaning and code optimization.
- Preparation of technical specifications and documentation.
- Working on project(s) with individual module responsibility.

AmaliTech Services, Ghana - Junior Associate Developer OCTOBER 2022 - JUNE 2023

DUTIES

- Develop views and components for responsive web apps.
- Assist with the analysis, design and development of software architecture and application design patterns
- Consume APIs with Axios and React Query hooks
- Code and test major features, as well as work jointly with other team members to deliver complex change within deadlines.
- Reviewed user requirements and created components, views, and advanced logic for feature implementation.

Skills

HTML 5

CSS 3

Tailwind CSS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

React.js

Next.js

Material UI

Daisy UI

Prime React

React Native

Mini Projects

MoviePop

Taskify

TheSpec Shop

Tools & Technologies

Git

NPM

PHP Storm

Visual Studio Code

Jira

Bitbucket

SonarQube

- Reporting regularly and proactively to the product owner regarding the progress of tasks and sprints.
- Facilitated the successful delivery of features on TheFairWork platform.
- Successfully reduced code smells by 80% through code review, optimization, and verification.
- Facilitated the successful development of TheFairWork blog to enable users to create and manage posts.
- Successfully increased the performance scores of TheFairWork platform on page speed insights to 90.
- Facilitated improving the security headers score of TheFairWork from B to A on securityheaders.com.

LANGUAGES

English
Fante (Native)

AmaliTech Services, Ghana - National Service Personnel (Front-End Developer and an Outreach Lead)
OCTOBER 2021- SEPTEMBER 2022

OUTREACH LEAD

- Assist in the development and implementation of the marketing plan to operationalize the commencement of The FairWork- a freelance platform that connects African Talents to businesses across the world who can benefit from their talent, hard work, and grit.
- Mining and compilation of emails and LinkedIn accounts of leads (potential clients) using LinkedIn.
- Design email copies and conduct outreach for TheFairwork.
- Perform A/B test and multivariate test to help validate email copies that enhance increased sign-up rate on The FairWork platform.
- Prepare outreach presentations and review all contracts between clients and freelancers.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Developed front-end views for TheFairWork platform using React.
- Optimized TheFairWork platform for maximum speed and scalability.
- Designed and created content for TheFairWork
- Created a user manual for all users on TheFairWork platform.
- Created blog posts to be featured in TheFairWork newsletter.

AmaliTech Services, Ghana - Internship

AUGUST 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Facilitated the collection of data pertaining to eligible trainees for their inaugural tuition-free IT graduate training initiative.
- Oversaw the administration of internal examinations for trainees.

TP Connect- Takoradi Technical University, Ghana - *Internship* JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

Education

Takoradi Technical University, Bachelor of Technology in Software Engineering JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Takoradi Technical University, Higher National Diploma in Information Technology

OCTOBER 2018 - AUGUST 2021

Certifications

<u>Learn HTML Course</u>	Codecademy	Nov. 2021
<u>Learn CSS Course</u>	Codecademy	Nov 2021
Command Line in Linux	Coursera	Dec. 2020
<u>Learn JavaScript Course</u>	Codecademy	Sep. 2021
Learn Intermediate JavaScript Course	Codecademy	Jan, 2022

Referees

Sharaf Deen Okyere | Manager | AmaliTech | sharaf.okyere@amalitech.com | +233 24 137 3704 | +233 50 528 4060 | +233 50 528 4060